I'm here with the recently re-signed
Saints defensive end Chris Rumph. How
are you? I'm great. How are you doing? I
am good. When you were going through
this process of free agency, how much
did you want to land right back here
with the Saints?
Oh man,
just going through this past season,
um
just being able to one second, I'm
sorry. You're right. Uh just being able
to go back and um think about what every
what I've been through and being able to
play 17 games, especially in a great
city like New Orleans and the fans, I
was excited to be back. Um I really
grown into doing it not only for myself
and my family, but for the city,
especially with all the history that uh
New Orleans has been through. Um so that
was the main thing of me wanting to come
back is being able to put put on for the
city, honestly.
What is it about the city and the fan
base that resonated with you so quickly?
Oh man, first of all, I'm from the
South. Uh so I I felt back at home.
Family was able to come to games and and
hang out with me afterwards. Um and then
I was able to just get that feel for
Southern football again. Obviously, you
know, nothing against the Chargers or
whatever. I was over there in the West
Coast, but y'all love football down here
and I I do too. And and the fans here
are amazing. I can't say enough about
the fans, honestly. And um just seeing
where this team was going at the end of
the year and and seeing the hype and and
the excitement around it. Obviously, you
want to be a part of that.
You mentioned that you played 17 games
last season. That's the first time
you've done that in your career, playing
every single game.
What was it about the way that you
approached last year that led to that
kind of success on the field?
I think God God was just, you know,
around me this year. He He blessed me
with being able to be healthy. Um
honestly, I didn't do anything different
um
than what I've done in the past. Um but
everything happens for a reason.
Obviously, the injuries with bone you
know, fractures and all that stuff, you
can't control that, but you know, ever
since I got those bone grafts in in my
foot, everything's been good. So,
um shout out to the the training staff
as well as uh being on top of
um everything that they do and giving me
the resources you know, to stay healthy
the whole year.
Being reunited with a former coach over
there with the Chargers and Brandon
Staley here, you were able to really
dive right in to what he wants to do
here defensively. How do you see the
scheme and what you guys are doing
building for next year?
Yeah, definitely building on what we uh
put on tape this past year. Uh the
physicality, being able to stop the run,
but also rush the passer and and got
have guys on the back end to cover the
the speedy guys. And you know, with the
the culture that we built um just the
one season alone, it was very special
and and you know, everybody was very
close-knit together.
Um you know, nobody was really arguing
anything. Every time you know, you go in
the building, it's you know, you're with
the boys. And so I think that's
something you don't take for granted.
And then knowing that, you know, heading
into free agency was definitely um
something I took into consideration.
You're always one of the personalities
that we like to talk to because you're
always in a good mood. You bring a lot
of energy. Where does that come from?
Uh my faith in Jesus, honestly, because
uh without him I wouldn't be here. And
and the things I've been through, um
and I stay faithful. I I know that
everything is going to work out in the
end. So, I that's where I get I get it
from because at the end of day, uh I'm
just a servant. And you know, I've been
put in position to where I can bless
others, you know, and and spread that
joy.
Um and then you know, tell people where
that comes from, just like you just did.
So, I think that's uh that's what I I'm
here to do. And uh obviously, you know,
being able to use the abilities that
he's blessed me with um to have a
platform to do that. All right, speaking
of the abilities, what are the goals for
this upcoming season? You did a little
special teams, a little defense last
year. Yeah, I definitely got some goals,
you know, uh special teams-wise,
definitely all-pro. I I got to get
all-pro. And then on defense, you know,
at least I got to get at least five
sacks and and help contribute to you
know, a Super Bowl winning defense.
Yeah, I mean Super Bowl sounds nice. I
think I can get on board with that, for
sure. Are you a NCAA March Madness
person? Ah, so a lot of people, you
know, first of all, shout out to my Duke
Blue Devils, you know, good job, guys.
You had me worried there for a second.
Um but they came through, but you know,
towards uh as I get older, I just a lot
of things, you know, I got taxes, I got
bills, I got all these things I got to
do.
Um but during this time, it's always fun
to watch March Madness and sit down and
you know, see guys um you know, live out
their dreams. You never know who's going
to win a game. I think that's the best
part is there's no
um there's no way for you to predict
who's going to win the national
championship. Every game is its own
entity, its own life. And I think I
enjoy that because it kind of translates
a lot to you know, this the season. Um
any given Sunday, I mean you got to show
up and if you don't, you might get your
butt kicked.
I know, I had to ask because obviously,
you went to Duke and they're the
favorite this year, for sure. Are you
coming back to New Orleans soon? What's
one of the first things you're going to
have to do? I'm going to Cafe Du Monde
again. I'm going to get my beignets. I'm
actually in Scottsdale, Arizona, so I've
I've been missing that that that good
old cooking down there, but um yeah,
definitely going to Cafe Du Monde.
Uh you know, going to locker room, you
know, seeing, "Hey, you know, my locker
is going to stay here this year." So, uh
that'll be fun.
Well, it's going to be great to have you
back here. Look forward to whenever you
do make the return and obviously,
getting the season going, it's right
around the corner. So, congratulations
and welcome back. Thank you. I can't
wait. Can't wait to be back.